Finding Aid for Michigan Environmental Council records, 1925-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Publications
  - Lansing Update
    - 1989 (Box 45)
    - 1990 (Box 45)
  - MEC Capital Update, 1994-1999 (Box 45)
  - Michigan Environmental Briefing Book, 1999-2004 (Box 45)
  - Press Releases
    - Solid Waste Press Conference, 1991 (Box 45)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 45)
    - 1993 (Box 45)
  - Print Design Evaluation, 1999 (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1997-2002 (Box 45)
- Videotapes
  The Video Tapes series includes a variety of MEC public service announcements and two episodes of a television program (Environmentally Speaking) on U-matic and VHS cassette tapes. These videos cover such topics as groundwater and wetlands protection, urban sprawl, and the health of the Great Lakes.
  - "Environmental Fund for Michigan" (Public Service Announcements), 1994; U-matic (Box 46)
  - Environmentally Speaking (Debut Show): "The Great Lakes Health Banner Project", undated; U-matic (Box 46)
  - Environmentally Speaking (Second Show): "The International Joint Commission", undated; U-matic (Box 46)
  - "Groundwater Protection: It's in Your Hands", 1993; VHS tape (Box 46)
  - "Groundwater Video Worktape 1", 1992; VHS (Box 46)
  - "Groundwater Video Worktape 2", 1992; VHS (Box 46)
  - "Our Valuable Wetland Resources" (Public Service Announcements), undated; U-matic (Box 46)
  - "Our Valuable Wetland Resources" (Public Service Announcements), undated; VHS (Box 46)
  - "Protecting Michigan's Wetlands" (Public Service Announcements), undated; VHS (Box 46)
  - "Sprawling Towards a New Century: Solutions for Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, and Washtenaw County", undated; VHS (Box 46)
  - "Survivors of the DEQ: Citizens Demand Reform of Michigan's Dept. of Environmental Quality", circa 2000; VHS (Box 46)
- Miscellaneous files: David Dempsey, Policy Director
  - Legislation and related, 1998-2000
    - Clean Michigan Initiative bond proposal, 1998 (Box 47)
    - Community Environmental Awareness Project, 1998 (Box 47)
    - Department of Environmental Quality (Box 47)
    - Department of Natural Resources (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous legislation (Box 47)
  - Michigan Public Service Commission
    - Motions, briefs, statements, and other documents submitted to the MPSC by the Michigan Environmental Council and others in the matter of applications made by various power companies, 2000-2001 (Box 48)
  - Electrical deregulation (Reports, memoranda, collected material), 1996-2000 (Box 49)
  - Pollution secrecy legislation (Michigan's environmental audit/privilege immunity bill), 1995-1996 (Box 49)
  - Wetlands permit legislation, 1996-1998 (Box 50)
  - Oil and gas drilling of Great Lakes bottom lands, 2001 (Box 50)
  - Reorganization: Dept. of Natural Resources, Dept. of Environmental Quality, 1995 (Box 50)
  - Nordhouse Dunes case, 1995-1998 (Box 50)
Related Material
The council's publications - Michigan Environmental Report and Coalition News have been placed in the Bentley Library's printed collection. The library also has a separate Lana Pollack collection relating to her career as a member of the Michigan State Legislature.